ANDREA C. BENTLEY

Duluth, GA 30096

Phone: 770-847-6763 | Email: andrea@bentleytech.com

LinkedIn: andrea-c-bentley | GitHub: AndreaGT91 | Portfolio: bentleytech.com

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with 7 years experience in accounting software development and over a decade in education support. Strong drive to create applications that are user-friendly, efficient, adhere to established standards, and are easily maintainable. Known for being thorough, dependable, an exceptional collaborator, yet able to work independently. View coworkers as teammates, not competitors.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Libraries/Frameworks: Javascript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, Node.js, Express, SQL, Sequelize, Mongoose, AJAX, Jest, Handlebars, React, JSX

Applications: Git, npm, MySQL, MongoDB, Visual Studio Code, Terminal, Slack, Zoom, Microsoft Office products: Word, Excel, Power Point, Publisher, Outlook, and Access, Google Drive applications: Docs, Sheets, and Slides

EDUCATION

Certificate of Completion in Web Development: Georgia Tech Professional Education Atlanta, GA (to be completed in August 2020)

Bachelor of Science in Information and Computer Science: *The Georgia Institute of Technology* Atlanta, GA, with Honor, Cooperative Program, Certificate Engineering Psychology

RELEVANT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer PACS Software

1995 – 1998

PACS Software

Alpharetta, GA
Redesigned legacy DOS-based Time and Billing application for Windows from the ground up using Delphi (object-oriented IDE for rapid application development) and TurboPower Orpheus.

Lead Engineer 1993 – 1995

Prentice Hall Professional Software

Smvrna. GA

Developed new features and updated business tax software with yearly tax law changes using Borland Pascal and TurboPower.

Software Analyst 1991 – 1993

Gerber Alley Norcross, GA

Analyzed client issues to find and solve software defects in hospital information system.

Cooperative Education Student

1987 - 1990

Southern Company Services

Atlanta, GA

Manned operating system support desk, developed project tracking application for database support team.

Additional Professional Experience

Registrar/Student Records Clerk

2016 – present Peachtree Corners, GA

Pinckneyville Middle School

Register new students, process withdrawals, fulfill records requests, manage student files, maintain student/parent information in database, create database queries as needed.

Substitute Teacher Gwinnett County Public Schools

2009 - 2016Suwanee, GA

Filled in for Teachers (Regular and Special Ed), Paraprofessionals, Resource, Office/Clerical,

Human Resources/Bookkeeper

and Clinic Worker.

2014 - 2015

North Metro Academy of Performing Arts

Norcross. GA

Processed payroll, coordinated employee benefits, paid bills, produced financial reports.

Lead Teacher/Assistant Teacher

2007 - 2010

Christ the King Preschool

Peachtree Corners. GA

Developed curriculum and lesson plans as lead teacher for one year, assisted lead teacher with implementing lessons for two years.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Troop Leader Service Unit Registrar 2007 - 2020

2008 - 2013

Girl Scouts of Greater Atlanta. Inc. - Norcross Service Unit

Norcross. GA

Troop Leader: organized fun, interactive, girl-led activities to support and encourage girls to earn badges and high awards. Registrar: process all registrations from the Norcross area; developed Access database to maintain registration information; assist with maintenance of organization's website.

Children's Ministries Volunteer

2004 – present

Simpsonwood United Methodist Church

Peachtree Corners, GA

Assisted with various roles in Vacation Bible School: Preschool Storyteller, Elementary Storyteller, and Shepherd. Taught Sunday School to various students, age 2 through 5th grade. Assisted Director with other projects, as needed.

PTA Volunteer

2004 - 2013

Simpson Elementary School

Peachtree Corners. GA

Coordinated parent volunteers for 5th grade musical and performed all necessary communication between Music Teacher and parents for the various Chorus performances. Choreographed and taught dance number for 5th grade musical. Assisted in Media Center and Reading Room by checking in/out books, shelving books, and performing inventory. Volunteered for various other events for both the whole school and for individual classroom. teachers.

Alumna Adviser

1994 - 2000

Alpha Gamma Delta Fraternity, Gamma Phi Chapter, Georgia Tech

Atlanta. GA

Advised collegiate officers: VP Finance - coordinated financial audit and completed annual tax return; Activities Coordinator - ensured all necessary paperwork was complete for insurance purposes.